<resources>
    <!--BUILDING ACTIVITY STRINGS-->

    <!--headers-->
    <string name="header">Building History</string>

    <!--building titles-->
    <string name="app_name">SeahawkTours</string>
    <string name="app_help">Display information about selected UNCW building.</string>
    <string name="cis_string">CIS Building</string>
    <string name="bear_string">Bear Hall</string>
    <string name="dobo_string">Dobo Hall</string>
    <string name="depaolo_string">Depaolo Hall</string>
    <string name="morton_string">Morton Hall</string>

    <!--building information-->
    <string name="bear_paragraph">
        Building History
        \n\n
        Bear Hall opened at its present site in 1972 as the home for the Business
        and Economics Departments. Currently, the Departments of Computer Science,
        Mathematics &amp; Statistics, and Philosophy &amp; Religion occupy classrooms,
        teaching labs and faculty offices. The College of Arts and Science also resides here.
        \n\n
        Namesake
        \n\n
        As the inscription on the plaque states Bear Hall is named for, "The original Isaac Bear
        Building, located at Market and 13th Streets, served as the first home of Wilmington College,
        outside the public school system. Classes were first held there in 1947." Constructed in 1912,
        the name of the first building was given by Samuel Bear, Jr. (1854-1916) as a memorial to his
        brother, Isaac Bear. The Bear family, owners of an intrastate wholesale dry goods firm located
        on Front Street, made a number of large donations to better the community such as a wing to James
        Walker Memorial Hospital. Isaac Bear was known as "one of Wilmington\'s most capable and highly
        esteemed businessmen." He was a member of North State Lodge of B\'Nai Brith, past Grand President
        of District Grand Lodge, and B.P.O.E Elks #532. Upon his death, the Isaac Bear Memorial School
        served to remember "the close friendship and devotion between the brothers and their interest in
        public welfare." The Order of the Isaac Bear is an honorary organization composed of faculty members
        that taught at the site of the original Wilmington College. Once the college built the new campus off
        of College Road, the Isaac Bear Building was torn down (1961).
        \n\n
    </string>
    <string name="cis_paragraph">
        Building History
        \n\n
        The Computer Information Systems (CIS) building was constructed to house the
        Information Systems and Operations Management Department from the Cameron School
        of Business and the Department of Computer Science from the College of Arts &amp;
        Sciences. The CIS Building, a new 51,731 square-foot state-of-the-art facility on
        the UNCW campus, opened January 10, 2007 for the new school semester. Work on the
        facility began on July 29, 2004 with the groundbreaking, and competed in December
        of 2006. The building cost approximately $12.8 million and was funded by the North
        Carolina State Bond campaign of 2000.
        \n\n
        Housed within the new building is the Financial Markets Room and, thanks to a donation
        from Edward Jones and over 50 if its financial advisers, the Edward Jones Financial Lab.
        Both rooms contain a stock board and ticker, however the Edward Jones Financial Lab also
        includes the Bloomberg Trading Terminal. With this terminal, students and faculty have the
        ability to trade stocks directly with the New York Stock Exchange, NASDAQ and more.
        \n\n
        The Department of Computer Science and the Department of Information Systems &amp; Operations
        Management are housed at CIS together and are jointly offering a Master of Science in Computer
        Science Information Systems (MSCSIS) degree, an intensive graduate program aimed at preparing
        the student to assume leadership roles in the development and implementation of computer and
        information systems.
        \n\n
    </string>
    <string name="dobo_paragraph">
        Building History
        \n\n
        Opened for use in 1996, the New Science Building contained classrooms, laboratories and faculty
        offices for the Chemistry and Biology Departments. Known as Dobo Hall since its 1999 dedication
        to the Dobo brothers, it is currently used by the Department of Biology and Marine Biology and the
        Department of Chemistry.
        \n\n
        Namesakes
        \n\n
        As both native sons and alumni of Wilmington College the brothers Dobo made their mark on the local
        community. Gabriel William (Bill), a World War II veteran came to the newly opened college in 1948
        and wrote a column for the "Seahawk" newspaper. Robert (Bob) Ridgely, also a veteran on World War II,
        attended Wilmington College in 1950. After completing their studies, the brothers established two private
        water companies - Cape Fear Utilities and Quality Water Supplies, which contributed to the growth of New
        Hanover County. Their businesses were sold to the City of Wilmington in 1999. As philanthropists, their
        generosity has sustained UNCW and other educational and humanitarian institutions throughout the state.
        The building\'s plaque inscription reflects their benevolent dedication, "The future of southeastern North
        Carolina is brighter as a result of their commitment to their hometown, Wilmington College and the University
        of North Carolina at Wilmington." Bob Dobo passed away April 28, 2009.
        \n\n
    </string>
    <string name="depaolo_paragraph">
        Building History
        \n\n
        DePaolo Hall was built in 1970 and was the original cafeteria on campus. After Wagoner Hall opened in 1989,
        the building was renamed Westside Hall because of its geographic location on campus. It houses student services
        including Abrons Student Health Center, CARE and Crossroads, University Testing Services, Disability Services,
        the University Learning Center, and University College. On April 29, 2011, the UNCW Board of Trustees announced
        the renaming of Westside Hall to DePaolo Hall in honor of Rosemary DePaolo, who retired June 30 after eight years
        as Chancellor. The naming recognizes Dr. DePaolo\'s leadership at UNCW and her commitment to put students first while
        accomplishing the ambitious strategic goals of her administration.
        \n\n
        Namesake
        \n\n
        Dr. Rosemary DePaolo was the Chancellor of the University of North Carolina Wilmington from 2003-2011. During her tenure
        as Chancellor of UNCW, she oversaw $250 million in construction projects. More than 40 percent of all students now live on
        campus. SAT entry scores and enrollment numbers rose considerably. Graduation rates exceeded the national average by more
        than 12 percent. In 2010 for the first time ever, US News and World Report ranked UNCW in the top 5 of public master\'s universities
        \in the South. The Princeton Review listed the Cameron School of Business as one of its featured 300 in the "Best Business Schools"
        guidebook edition. UNCW was also named one of the nation\'s "most military friendly" schools for the second year in a row by G.I. Jobs.
        \n\n
        Dr. DePaolo previously served at Georgia Southern University, Western Carolina University, and then as president of Georgia College and
        State University. She holds a doctorate in 18th-century English literature. The Long Island native is married to a retired English professor.
        \n\n
    </string>
    <string name="morton_paragraph">
        Building History
        \n\n
        Opened as the Humanities Building in 1978, it was renamed as Morton Hall in an April 1981 dedication. Morton Hall currently houses classrooms
        and offices for the English Department, Creative Writing Program, History Department, as well as the multi-purpose Bryan Auditorium.
        \n\n
        Namesake
        \n\n
        Miss Margaret "Shannon" Morton, a native of Clarksville, Virginia received her BA from Longwood College in Virginia. Her Master of Arts in English
        was earned at Peabody College in Tennessee, with additional graduate work completed at UNC-Chapel Hill and William and Mary College. As one of the
        original faculty members at Wilmington College, Miss Morton holds the title of many "firsts." She was the first full time teacher hired, the first
        teacher in the Department of English (1947-1963), and the first Chairman of the English Department. From 1955-1965 she was the Dean of Women as well
        as the advisor to the writing club "Pen Pushers." She retired in 1965 as professor emeritus. Morton Hall\'s dedication plaque reflects on her service,
        "The high standards of academic achievement she set for herself and for her students symbolizes the high ideals, dedication and enthusiasm essential
        to teaching excellence in institutions of higher education."
        \n\n
    </string>

    <!--buliding captions-->
    <string name="bear_caption">This is a bear</string>
    <string name="cis_caption">This is the CIS Building</string>
    <string name="dobo_caption">This is Dobo Hall</string>
    <string name="depaolo_caption">This is Depaolo Hall</string>
    <string name="morton_caption">This is Morton Hall</string>

    <!--building link-->
    <string name="building_for_more">For more information visit: </string>
    <string name="bear_link">https://library.uncw.edu/web/collections/archives/bnl/19.html</string>
    <string name="cis_link">https://library.uncw.edu/web/collections/archives/bnl/cis.html</string>
    <string name="dobo_link">https://library.uncw.edu/web/collections/archives/bnl/25.html</string>
    <string name="depaolo_link">https://library.uncw.edu/web/collections/archives/bnl/6.html</string>
    <string name="morton_link">https://library.uncw.edu/web/collections/archives/bnl/18.html</string>

    <!--ABOUT PAGE STRINGS-->

    <!--header-->
    <string name="action_about">About</string>


    <!--info-->
    <string name="about_created_by">Created by Ryan McIntyre</string>
    <string name="about_link">UNCW building information and images courtesy of the UNCW <a href="https://library.uncw.edu/web/collections/archives/landmarks.html">UNIVERSITY ARCHIVES</a></string>


    <!--SHARE action-->
    <string name="action_share">Share</string>
    <string name="share_building_info">Check out this UNCW building information for UNCW\'s&#160;</string>
    <string name="main_list_text">Or click one of the following UNCW buildings to view more information: </string>


    <!-- OTHER STRINGS -->
    <string name="button_text">Click to get nearest building</string>
    <string name="location_on">REMINDER: Location permissions turned ON</string>
    <string name="location_off">REMINDER: Location permissions turned OFF</string>

</resources>
